Miguel Angel Ricaño

FULL STACK DEVELOPER

SUMMARY

I'm a Full Stack Developer with great love to build apps to solve today's problems, who also dominate the arts of organization, negotiation, and mediation. Clean code and user experience are a must, fluent in multiple languages, frameworks, and technologies, and capable of ramping up quickly and efficiently.

EXPERIENCE

Microverse, Remote

Code Reviewer | March 2021 - Present

• More than 200 projects reviewed, and counting, with varied front-end and back-end projects.

IK Sustainable, Xalapa, Mexico

eCommerce Manager | May 2020 - Present

- The total development of the electronic business took me less than 2 months.
- For this project. I learned liquid in less than two weeks.
- The website that I create gets more than 2500 visits per day thanks to the SMO and SEO that I developed.

The Rolland Collection, Bordeaux, France

Business Manager for LATAM and Asia | January 2012 - May 2014

- In the first 6 months, the management doubled the number of people under my supervision, thanks to the excellent initial results.
- 30% increased sales in Asia and 15% in Latin America in less than a year.

Budhi, Mexico City, Mexico

Founder & Director | August 2010 - November 2011

- We developed Maat software, the first administrative software in the country with a freemium model, built to emulate the decisions of professional admins applied to micro and small businesses that did not have access to administrative software.
- In 2011, Grupo Carso acquired Budhi, and its software "Maat", to add it to its catalog of free services for small businesses.

EDUCATION

Microverse | 2020 - 2021

Remote Full Stack Web Development Program, Full Time

- I spent 1300+ hours mastering algorithms, data structures, and full-stack development while simultaneously developing projects with Ruby, Rails, JavaScript, React, and Redux.
- I developed skills in remote pair-programming using GitHub, industry-standard gitflow, and daily standups to communicate and collaborate with international remote developers.

EBS Paris - European Business School | 2012 -2014

Master of Business Administration, International Business Management (Incomplete)

Universidad Veracruzana | 2005 - 2010

Bachelor of Business Administration, International Business Management

www.miguelricano.me <u>Github</u> | <u>Linkedin</u> mricanho@gmail.com

SKILLS

Front-End: JavaScript, React, Redux, HTML5, CSS3

Back-End: Ruby, Rails, PostgreSQL, Liquid

Tools & Methods: Git, GitHub, Heroku, Netlify, Mobile/Responsive Development, RSpec, TDD, Chrome Dev Tools

Professional: Remote Pair-Programming, Teamwork, Mentoring

PROJECTS

EasyWeather

- EasyWeather is a project to display the temp and weather's condition of the desired city in a cute way.
- Built with JavaScript, HTML5, Bulma.
- -Repository here.

Sustyle

- This is Sustyle, the website focused on the latest sustainability articles.
- Ruby on Rails, Ruby, Bulma, PostgreSQL.
- -Repository <u>here</u>.

VOLUNTEER

Mentor, Microverse As a volunteer mentor, I help new students to understand and develop in the new and

demanding microverse work environment.

LANGUAGES

Spanish, Native English, C1 French, B1